<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Salebarn</title>
    <description>SALEBARN is about DISTRIBUTED FREEDOM. We extend FREE and accelerated discovery and negotiation technology to provide greater transparency, value, information from FREE and open markets.</description>
    <link>/</link>
    <atom:link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2017 21:42:14 -0600</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2017 21:42:14 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.1.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Prospecting Funnel</title>
        <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;the-ideas-to-value-funnel&quot;&gt;The Ideas-To-Value Funnel&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This post is about PROSPECTING, first and foremost – it’s NOT a get-rich-quick scheme. It is NOT about getting morons to buy your worthless second-rate product.  It is NOT about getting your share of a shrinking pie – although competition definitely matters and there’s a place for advocating, advertising and promoting a good idea – this process is about fundamentally increasing the size of the pie. At its core it is fundamentally a build-a-wealth-foundation-in-an-antifragile-manner approach that relies upon the simple construct of a funnel or sieve to look at the universe of ideas and to narrow the universe down to a practical set of things that represent the highest and best value of your time in terms of things that you can enjoy working on in order to accelerate the process of to provide legitimate value for others [and yourself].&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The universe of what humans understand is constantly expanding but it will NEVER EVER catch up with the actual full universe of Reality. This process is fundamentally about falling in love with Reality … and diligently working at loving Reality as it really is going to be, not the fairy princess Reality that you hope Reality might be, not the shrinking hard Reality that you fear Reality might be, and certainly NOT the tiny, little narrow Reality that you’ve always thought it was … you must love Reality as the constantly expanding genuine Reality that Reality is always going to be in the future, even as you remain skeptical of whether you really know the true Reality or not. Prospecting is about being in love with and being one with Reality … discernment of true Reality is FUNDAMENTALLY a spiritual process of discovery.  Since it is necessarily, outside-the-politicized-HUMAN-box, but within the constraints of true Reality, prospecting is fundamentally NOT a process of submission to the values of a cult or NOT a process of submission to the mores, rules and rituals of a cult.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;i-your-perspective-restricts-your-universe-of-ideas&quot;&gt;I. Your perspective restricts your UNIVERSE of ideas&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The FIRST restrictor in the funnel is about largely involuntary restrictions on your perspective.  Instead of NARROWING this perspective – we want to think about works at EXPANDING your horizons and really achieving this is HARD.  VERY hard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How large is your perspective?  You might imagine that it’s already pretty sizable and bigger than than your father’s perspective – you might imagine that it is absolutely YUUGE.  It isn’t.  Especially not when it comes to what your potential perspective could and should be, you have a smaller-than-average-of-your-potential perspective, at best, it’s maybe a 40th-percentile perspective … your “tiny dick” of a perspective might LOOK large to you, it just isn’t … it only appears that way because of your affluence-addled thinking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Regardless of how large it is, it has to get a lot bigger. For example, your horizons necessarily have to be much LARGER than everything that you can merely Google … if you don’t routinely find things with NO SEARCH RESULTS on Google, you need to think about things that might expanding your perspective – Google’s world of indexed content is not only biased by the Google’s proprietary search (i.e. Google ad-revenue maximization) algorithm … the realm of what any corporately-restricted politically-correct dismissive mind-shrinking company like Google even knows about is far, far, far too narrow.  The starting perspective of everything you can see on your horizon has to much be larger than Google’s – you must be capable of thinking beyond Google’s EVIL little search box and knowing that your perspective is too small is PART of what it will take for you to expand your perspective.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the necessary things you must do in order to expand your perspective is to stop wasting time fitting into human boxes … it’s beyond reducing the time you spend doing those non-value-added human activities you already detest but tolerate and accept, like waiting [at a doctor’s appointment, in line at a cash register, at the DMV], driving and paying attention to traffic … you may also need to reduce the time you spend watching TV, looking at things online, reading books, merely following other ideas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You probably need to increase the amount of spend time in nature, hiking, walking, thinking, meditating, praying, fasting or engaged in the duties of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Extreme-Ownership-U-S-Navy-SEALs-ebook/dp/B00VE4Y0Z2&quot;&gt;extreme ownership&lt;/a&gt; of the your known material realm … it’s not just housekeeping, but that too – it’s about maintaining and optimizing, performing 5S activities and making hard choices to ELIMINATE baggage … fully OWNING your life in an extreme manner is HARD work … I do not recommend ingesting drugs, but if you train in an extreme manner like &lt;a href=&quot;http://davidgoggins.com/about/&quot;&gt;David Goggins&lt;/a&gt; your body is equipped to produce mind-altering biochemicals for perspective-enhancing biochemicals. Affluent humans avoid such privations – accordingly, human perspective is increasing &lt;em&gt;bovinized&lt;/em&gt; – humans no longer [have to] engage in existentially-threatening treks across ice flows to hunt mastadons and experience gigantic increases in perspective – instead we are content to herded like cattle as long as food and free veterinary care are provided so that we never suffer.  Never suffering or even failing to suffer on a daily basis has perspective-atrophying consequences – affluence is why you have a “tiny dick” of a perspective, regardless of how large Google makes you think your “little dick” of a perspective is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The need to engage in extreme training, fasting, praying, meditating is NOT me-too been-there-done-that spiritual-shopping bucket-list material; this is about legitimate spiritual DISCOVERY that results serendipitous fashion when you get your mind tough enough to 60% of the perspectives that almost everyone misses because they do just like what Google does and quits at 40% or far less of what is out there.  If you are serious about expanding your horizons, don’t waste your time in the narrowed-down, dumbed-down digital realm of Google or Facebook or Wikipedia – instead, increase the amount of time you spend in spiritual discovery and discipline to be able to do the training necessary for things like ultra marathons or attempting the type of extremely harrowing pilgrimages or quests for vision, eg the process of biking from Alaska to Argentina is NOT about seeing the scenery that you could find on Google Maps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;ii-sticky-monetizable-ideas-that-at-minimum-lend-themselves-to-loyalty-programs-and-distributed-peer-to-peer-ledger-database-accountability&quot;&gt;II. Sticky, monetizable ideas that, at minimum, lend themselves to loyalty programs and distributed peer-to-peer ledger database accountability&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second restrictor in this prospecting funnel is about narrowing your choices from your BIG PERSPECTIVE.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Specifically, the second restrictor is constraining the set of all possible ideas in the universe, to the set of ideas that are valuable enough that they could possibly make money. That might sound SEVERELY pecuniary, but you must consider several things: 1) Someone has to pay for this; there is absolutely no escaping that – someone must pay. If you don’t want to rely upon money that is coercively stolen from others, your overall process has to be financially self-sustaining.. 2) The first restrictor is NOT about what makes the most money; it is simply about whether you can see a potential path to monetization or not. 3) As you work the funnel and work the ideas, serendipitous discoveries will be byproducts of the process.  As long as you are WORKING in the realm of IDEAS that are may be of monetary value to other productive human beings who have money [and not simply scams to get or take things from other human beings OR to merely be wealthy, powerful or famous], you will discover new things that are inordinately valuable to others, even those without money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The realm of ideas that could be shaped into things that MAKE MONEY is larger than human can contemplate – it’s larger than the current global economy, since that economy is necessarily constrained by &lt;em&gt;the centralizers&lt;/em&gt; of wealth, power and fame … &lt;em&gt;the centralizers&lt;/em&gt; are not the tiny minority of people who are inordinately capable and thus justifiably hold most of the human wealth OR those who have most of the power OR those who have most of the fame.  &lt;em&gt;The centralizers&lt;/em&gt; are the sychophants who believe that the wealthy, powerful and famous should have even more wealth, power and fame AND, the galling and DEFINITIVE part is that, &lt;em&gt;the centralizers&lt;/em&gt; believe that government’s monopoly on violence should be used to coercively concentrate even more wealth, power and fame.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This means that &lt;em&gt;the centralizers&lt;/em&gt; are those would gladly do WHATEVER IT TAKES to &lt;em&gt;suck the cocks&lt;/em&gt; of the very wealthy, very powerful, very famous in order to gain their favor, to be like them. &lt;em&gt;The centralizers&lt;/em&gt; do not belong to a formal organization … it’s not conspiracy of the the Masons, the Illuminati, the Council on Foreign Relations, the IMF, Central Banks … &lt;em&gt;the centralizers&lt;/em&gt; are aggressively engaged in their cocksucking out of respect – they want to suck cock in exchange for a perch next to throne, a seat at the table or a benefit-laden role in oppressing people, legally stealing assets and attention and generally squelching development of new ideas.  The development of &lt;em&gt;the centralizer&lt;/em&gt; CLASS is not a conspiracy, but an artifact of how humans are hard-wired for the innate depravities and failures of intelligence that lead to classism – human gregariousness leads to gatherings, sorting, pecking orders, and the lynch mobification of democracies that promotes the scum of impurities settling on the “top” … except the “top” is not a legitimate top, but an artificially-built Tower of Babel constructed from the toughest materials of human depravity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Monetization strategies, therefore, should be constructed to serve ALL people equitably, but we should look at who can pay and why they would voluntarily choose to pay.  The carrot, or “value proposition” is fundamentally about increasing productivity, increasing income. The stick, or what is withheld until payment is recievied is about monopoly … or market differentiation … matters – the money does have to come from somewhere; it’s always possible to give a good product away and there are very legitimate and shrewd business reasons for open sourcing a product, monetizing the more valuable offerings … open source is partly a defense against competitors, by growing your own herd of competitors [and perhaps staying a step ahead of them] AND as a way to interact with early adopters.  But at some point, open source is also about just giving away ideas because you have so damned many of them!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To most effectively look at monetization, we need to look at HOW money works and why humans use money.  Money has been the way human beings keep score. It will probably always be necessary for humans to keep score with some sort of loyalty system or way to incentivize participation. Enlightened monetization, therefore, is really a matter of removing the waste, fraud and abuse from the score-keeping systems humans use to track wealth. An example of a more efficient, robust and anti-fragile score-keeping system are the metrics used by Github. Earlier, but still important score-keeping systems were the reputation management systems of Ebay or StackExchange.  Before that were things like frequently-flier miles, hotel loyalty programs and free-sandwich punchcards used by fast food vendors … before that we can look at things like Gold Bond stamps or Betty Crocker points.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;iii-thiels-zero-to-one-and-laying-the-foundations-for-the-the-most-scalable-biggest-impact-ideas&quot;&gt;III. Thiel’s Zero-to-One and laying the foundations for the the most scalable, biggest impact ideas.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The startup cookbook approach is the next set of funnels and sieves.  There are seven big Questions that all potential business ideas must consider – these Questions effectively provide ways of winnowing down the massive amount of ideas we have in the hopper.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Engineering Question&lt;/strong&gt;:
Can you create breakthrough technology (vs. incremental improvement)?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Timing Question&lt;/strong&gt;:
Is now the right time to start this particular business?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Monopoly Question&lt;/strong&gt;:
Are you starting with a big share of a small market?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The People Question&lt;/strong&gt;:
Do you have the right team?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Distribution Question&lt;/strong&gt;:
Do you have a way to not just create but &lt;strong&gt;deliver&lt;/strong&gt; your product?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Durability Question&lt;/strong&gt;:
Will your market position be defensible 10 and 20 years into the future?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Secret Question&lt;/strong&gt;:
Have you identified a unique opportunity that others don’t see?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;AFTER we narrowed our list in this fashion, the next thing to look at is SCALEABILITY … that is basically the next heading.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;iv-scalability-and-antifragile-community-husbandry-processes&quot;&gt;IV. Scalability and antifragile community husbandry processes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Professional brand management and different social commerce strategies are starting to mature. We can look at what works, what doesn’t.  What we are really looking at here are inclusive networks with built-in incentive structures (see above material) that go beyond merely spreading ideas, but enlist people to take them further, develop and extend the ideas for their purposes and yet continue to participate in advancing the value proposition of the general idea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This stages gets to be partly about LETTING GO … not just giving others the opportunity to USE and OWN the idea, but encouraging them to hack something bigger.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2017 11:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>/philosophy/2017/02/02/Prospecting-Funnel.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/philosophy/2017/02/02/Prospecting-Funnel.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>Philosophy</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The FULL significance of the 12 Factor App mindset</title>
        <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;twelve-factor-appshttp12factornet-have-become-absolutely-necessary-in-the-softare-as-a-service-realm--but-there-is-a-lucky-13th-factor-that-is-essential-for-new-work&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://12factor.net/&quot;&gt;Twelve Factor apps&lt;/a&gt; have become absolutely NECESSARY in the softare-as-a-service realm … but there is a LUCKY 13th factor that is essential for NEW work.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The twelve factors given below are not goals; they are requirements.  If we cannot meet the &lt;a href=&quot;http://12factor.net/&quot;&gt;twelve factor&lt;/a&gt; requirements, we should not pollute the world with our careless, reckless, ill-conceived app.  The &lt;a href=&quot;http://12factor.net/&quot;&gt;twelve factor&lt;/a&gt; format is inspired by Martin Fowler’s books &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.safaribooksonline.com/library/view/patterns-of-enterprise/0321127420/&quot;&gt;Patterns of Enterprise Application Architecture and Refactoring&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the 12 factors need to reconcieved … in less trusting, less naive, more paranoid manner  that focuses on security rather than feature bloat. A much less trusting mindset is necessary develop more secure, reliable, scalable, survivable system … fundamentally, this means that the back-end datastores must be designed for survivability, in radically more decentralized and more distributed, &lt;em&gt;eg at least CockroachDB, probably blockchain&lt;/em&gt; … the MOST necessary thing about an app happens BEFORE you start PRACTICING WRITING CODE for a new product … BEFORE YOU START monkeying around with code, before you start thinking about architecture, it is important to not just conceive of a new [incrementally-better] product [because that’s what you will do AFTER you have a new product] … the first thing that you must do is reconceive the customers for a new emergent product … the process of becoming [something more], becoming emergent must be and can be continually created, re-created, reconceived.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This means moving from an “Application Platform-as-a-Service” to a “Container Platform-as-a-Service” to in order to enable &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/cockroachdb/cockroach#design&quot;&gt;a more highly distributed SQL database with support for ACID transactions, horizontal scalability and survivability&lt;/a&gt;.  The ultimate intent is a radically more diffuse, distributed, decentralized transaction database using blockchain architecture.  In highly distributed systems [like bitcoin], suspicion, pessimism and paranoia are used as architecture requirements to build highly reliable systems from extremely unreliable, untrustworthy components … which is possible by focusing on the most core elements of a transaction and assuming throughout the design process that all nodes and channels of the network, as well as all bots or participants that might use the system are untrustworthy even potentially malicious.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the 12 Factor App mindset STILL matters … let’s look at WHY.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;i-version-controlled-codebase--blog&quot;&gt;I. Version-Controlled Codebase / Blog&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There can be many deployments, but a twelve-factor app is ALWAYS tracked in a version control system, such as Git, Mercurial, or Subversion. ALWAYS! ALWAYS! ALWAYS!  And “ALWAYS!” means that it necessary to center an workflow around the code repositories in version control system … for example, meetings should not be physical, but instead be conducted via repository-centric chat with archived transcripts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;ii-dependencies&quot;&gt;II. Dependencies&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A twelve-factor app never relies on implicit existence of system-wide packages. It declares all dependencies, completely and exactly, via a dependency declaration manifest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;iii-config&quot;&gt;III. Config&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The twelve-factor app stores config in environment variables (often shortened to env vars or env). Env vars are easy to change between deploys without changing any code; unlike config files, there is little chance of them being checked into the code repo accidentally. In a twelve-factor app, env vars are granular controls, each fully orthogonal to other env vars. They are never grouped together as “environments”, but instead are independently managed for each deploy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;iv-backing-services&quot;&gt;IV. Backing Services&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A backing service is any service the app consumes over the network as part of its normal operation. Examples include datastores (such as MySQL or CouchDB), messaging/queueing systems (such as RabbitMQ or Beanstalkd), SMTP services for outbound email (such as Postfix), and caching systems (such as Memcached). The code for a twelve-factor app made no distinction between local and third party services. To the app, both are attached resources, accessed via a URL or other locator/credentials stored in the config … but our new architecture requirements will force to build highly reliable backing service systems from extremely unreliable, untrustworthy components.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;v-build-release-run&quot;&gt;V. Build, release, run&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The twelve-factor app uses strict separation between the build, release, and run stages. Every release should always have a unique release ID, such as a timestamp of the release (such as 2011-04-06-20:32:17) or an incrementing number (such as v100). Releases are an append-only ledger and a release cannot be mutated once it is created. Any change MUST create a new release.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;vi-processes&quot;&gt;VI. Processes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Twelve-factor processes are necessarily stateless and must be constructed so that they don’t persist and share almost nothing. The rare data that needs to persist must be stored in a stateful backing service, typically a highly-distributed database system. The memory space or filesystem of the process should be used as a momentarily brief, single-transaction cache pulling from a &lt;em&gt;Cockroach-ey&lt;/em&gt; database system with support for ACID transactions, horizontal scalability and survivability](https://github.com/cockroachdb/cockroach#design).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;vii-port-binding&quot;&gt;VII. Port binding&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The twelve-factor app is completely self-contained and does not rely on runtime injection of a webserver into the execution environment to create a web-facing service. Typically, the web app exports HTTP as a service by binding to a port, and listening to requests coming in on that port. HTTP is not the only service that can be exported by port binding. Nearly any kind of server software can be run via a process binding to a port and awaiting incoming requests. Examples include ejabberd (speaking XMPP), and Redis (speaking the Redis protocol).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;viii-concurrency&quot;&gt;VIII. Concurrency&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the twelve-factor app, processes are a first class citizen. Processes in the twelve-factor app take strong cues from the &lt;a href=&quot;http://adam.herokuapp.com/past/2011/5/9/applying_the_unix_process_model_to_web_apps/&quot;&gt;unix process model for running service daemons&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;ix-disposability&quot;&gt;IX. Disposability&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The twelve-factor app’s processes must be disposable and destroyable, meaning they must be started or stopped at a moment’s notice … the more temporary the better. This facilitates fast elastic scaling, rapid deployment of code or config changes, and robustness of production deploys.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;x-devprod-parity&quot;&gt;X. Dev/prod parity&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The twelve-factor app is designed for continuous deployment by making the gap between development and production as small as possible… make the time gap small … make the personnel gap small … make the tools gap small.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;xi-logs&quot;&gt;XI. Logs&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A twelve-factor app never concerns itself with routing or storage of its output stream. It should not attempt to write to or manage logfiles – it must assume that logging will tend to attract malicious use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;xii-admin-processes&quot;&gt;XII. Admin processes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Run admin/management tasks as one-off processes. One-off admin processes should be run in an identical environment as the regular long-running processes of the app. They run against a release, using the same codebase and config as any process run against that release. Admin code must ship with application code to avoid synchronization issues.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 11:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>/philosophy/2017/01/01/Do-12-Factor-Apps-Still-Matter.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/philosophy/2017/01/01/Do-12-Factor-Apps-Still-Matter.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>Philosophy</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The state of the economic data industry</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Not all data are created equally.  Some data really matter because they are the artifacts of serious choice by people with scarce resources to allocate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Data that is an artifact of a REAL economic transaction is actually really valuable, by comparison … if we consider things like a search engine requests or some sort of social media inference or psueudo-meaningful quasi-real transaction, eg. a “Like” on FB or LinkedIn or upvote on StackExchange, with sort of just data about potential interests or preferences or even boredom.  Things change significantly when real money gets spent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One example of a company nudging in the more meaningful niche in this realm is &lt;a href=&quot;https://metamarkets.com/blog/&quot;&gt;MetaMarkets&lt;/a&gt; which specializes in programmatic ad [and ad buy data, analytics and tracking data, etc] using its own technology stack that is built end-to-end for speed, flexibility, and the power to handle huge volumes of programmatic ad data. Programmatic advertising dwarfs Wall Street in data volume, growth, and complexity. It is arguably one of the most complex marketplaces ever created and it’s still being created everyday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another company with a more active strategy to acquire more valuable data is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.premise.com/&quot;&gt;Premise&lt;/a&gt;, an economic data collection and aggregation company, which just received &lt;a href=&quot;http://techcrunch.com/2015/09/24/premise-raises-50-million-to-outsource-the-collection-of-economic-data/&quot;&gt;$50 million in series C funding&lt;/a&gt;. Premise is a SaaS provider that uses 25,000 “contributors” in 32 countries and tasks them with photographing and otherwise documenting economic data in order to provide customers like the World Bank with highly valuable information. Premise has boots on the ground who will show up at grocery stores and send back information that Premise’s data analysts then parse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are other opportunities in economic data being created every second; for example, we can think about rapidly emerging communities like crowdfunding or bitcoin that did not exist a decade ago OR we can think about how &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.programmableweb.com/news/5-ways-to-increase-api-adoption/analysis/2015/06/12&quot;&gt;data and data APIs have become the means for building communities and expanding networks&lt;/a&gt;.  Markets that more free than ever is particularly interesting and that is the realm that Salebarn is exploring … things like peer-to-peer distributed exchanges, smart contracts and revolutions that continue to break out in freelancing, remote working, microwork, app hubs and developments like &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/college-cryptocurrency-network/reposium-dco-the-future-of-wikipedia-4be080cfa027&quot;&gt;reposium&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jun 2016 12:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>/data/2016/06/25/MetaMarkets-Economic-Data.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/data/2016/06/25/MetaMarkets-Economic-Data.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>Data</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Conway&#39;s Law and Why GitHub Matters</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Conway%27s_law&quot;&gt;Conway’s Law&lt;/a&gt; tells us that &lt;em&gt;organizations which design systems … are constrained to produce designs which are copies of the communication structures of these organizations.&lt;/em&gt;  This means that the political organizations and Parties that have been trying to elect political leaders, ie the Democrats, the GOP, the third Party efforts, are all going to fail at changing government because their organizations are inherently corrupted by old politicos, thoroughly calcified and cannot do anything other than produce the same old crap that they always have.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hopefully you already an appreciation for the open source distributed version control system &lt;a href=&quot;https://git-scm.com/&quot;&gt;Git&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&quot;http://aosabook.org/en/git.html&quot;&gt;history of and rationale behind the development of Git&lt;/a&gt; … and maybe you understand a bit of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.quora.com/What-makes-GitHub-such-an-important-and-strategic-web-property&quot;&gt;what the GitHub social coding ecosystem is about&lt;/a&gt; or how &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wired.com/2015/03/github-conquered-google-microsoft-everyone-else/&quot;&gt;GitHub conquered Microsoft and Google and everyone else&lt;/a&gt; and what &lt;a href=&quot;https://help.github.com/articles/be-social/&quot;&gt;being social&lt;/a&gt; and then &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.github.com/program/&quot;&gt;extending Github platform&lt;/a&gt; is about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wired.com/2015/03/github-conquered-google-microsoft-everyone-else/&quot;&gt;Open source socially-produced code has formally now arrived&lt;/a&gt; because the most savvy DevOps engineers thoroughly understand why collaborating on an open source team is not only fun and that the collaborative effort also “moves the ball ahead” for everyone … there’s a private intrinsic reward, but with the &lt;a href=&quot;https://help.github.com/categories/graphs-and-contributions/&quot;&gt;GitHub graphs and contributions metrics&lt;/a&gt; there is also the direct professional recognition [and possible financial reward] that comes from the public trail of commits, pull requests, gists, issues, comments, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Github is a means to an end, but the MEANS to that end are critically important.  It’s important to reiterate what &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Conway%27s_law&quot;&gt;Conway’s Law&lt;/a&gt; tells us about &lt;em&gt;organizations which design systems … being constrained to produce designs which are copies of the communication structures of these organizations.&lt;/em&gt;  A solid implementation of market-based technologies that furnish more options and greater choice and transcend government … but that effort is, FIRST and FOREMOST, about creating the technologies that enable a leaner, smaller, saner, less coercive, more reliable government.  That is exactly what is happening right now through open source communication architectures and social production workflows of the type that were designed and built into Git and the GitHub platform and are &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.github.com/program/&quot;&gt;constantly being extended and improved&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 03:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>/technology/2015/09/09/Why-GitHub-Matters.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/technology/2015/09/09/Why-GitHub-Matters.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>Technology</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
